theartstack.com 2018-12-29

# ArtStack - art online

You (and your love of art!) are at the centre of everything we do. We want to maintain your trust by handling your personal information with respect and putting you in control. We want you to know what personal information ArtStack Limited (known here as "we" or “ArtStack") collects about you, and how we use it.

We seek to make our explanations short and easy to understand. But, if you’d like further information, or have any questions, please contact our Data Protection Officer using the details in the ‘Contact’ section below.

If we ever make any major changes to our privacy practices, we’ll let you know. If necessary, we’ll also ask for your permission.

**Privacy Notice**

Our Privacy Notice has been designed with our users as our first priority. How the notice applies to you will depend on the way in which you interact with us. For example, if you:

1) set-up or use an account with us, we use the information you provide us to deliver our service (a social discovery platform for art), and, where permitted, keep you up to date about art you might find interesting on the site and users who follow you, or who might seek to purchase your work (for ArtStack Pro users); and

2) when you browse our site, we use cookies to tailor your experience and hopefully provide you with a seamless experience.

Your choices and rights under each scenario are explained in more detail below.

**What Information We Have & Where We Get It ** **We collect and store different types of information about you when you create an account, buy the ArtStack Pro service, contact us, and use our websites or app.**

  * When you create an account, buy ArtStack Pro or are invited to the service by a friend, we will collect your information - which may include your contact and billing information. When you sign-up with Facebook or use social media sharing features within ArtStack, we may receive some additional information about you, which is explained in that process (for Facebook, we limit this to a minimal amount of information, i.e. location and gender).

  * We also keep track of the frequency of your visits, what artworks you’ve added, ‘stacked’, or commented on, what artists or other tags you follow, the number of followers you have and those that you follow, and any invites that you’ve sent.

  * When you use our websites or apps, we collect information such as the browser and device you're using, your IP address, your location, the site you came from, what you did and didn't use our site/app for, or the site you visit when you leave us.

**How We Use Your Information & Why **

We collect and use your information for lots of reasons such as helping you see art by artists you like, sharing news, for marketing and as otherwise required by law.

1) For the performance of our contract with you

We use your information when you enter into a contract with us (for example to buy the ArtStack Pro service) so we can:

  * process your order

  * take payment, and

  * provide you with customer support.

2) For our legitimate business interests

  * To conduct market research and analysis which helps improve and customise our products and services.

  * For our marketing purposes, unless your consent is required for such marketing (see section 3 below).

  * To send you customer service emails.

  * To prevent or detect unlawful behaviour, to protect or enforce our legal rights or as otherwise permitted by law. As such, we may use your information to prevent misuse of our intellectual property (e.g. our website), fraud, or other crimes.

  * To create a profile about you to offer our service, which is by nature personalised. For example, if you like a particular artist, we may email you regarding new artworks by that artist that have been added to ArtStack, or about an exhibition of the artist’s work that is in your city. We make sure our messages and website are relevant to you based on your profile.

  * Where you’ve given your consent

  * To contact you with information or offers regarding our products or services – this may be via email, via push notifications, via SMS, or social media platforms. You can change your marketing preferences at any time, see “Your choices and rights” section below.

  * To provide you with location based services – like through our event section in our website or app, to see what events are taking place nearby

  * To deliver tailored advertising on our websites and apps (see our Cookies Policy for more information].

**Who We Share Your Data With & Why ** **We may share elements of your information with third parties to offer our service. These include:**

  * Our third-party service providers (sometimes known as data processors) such as cloud computing providers who provide the IT infrastructure on which our products and systems are built.

  * If you seek to buy or sell art via our platform, we may disclose your information to the buyer or seller (as applicable) to negotiate and complete the transaction.

  * Government agencies or other authorised bodies where permitted or required by law.

  * Any successor to all or part of our business.

**Your Choices & Rights **

Among other rights, you can choose if you’d like to receive marketing from us. You also have the right to access the information we have about you. Where you have given us your consent, you can withdraw it by doing the following:

  * To stop receiving our marketing you can change your preferences within your account, follow the unsubscribe instructions in any of the emails we send you or contact us and we will do it for you.

  * To opt out of the use of cookies and tracking tools, please see our Cookies Policy.

  * To opt out of location tracking and push notifications, you can change the settings on your device or keep your location off.

**You also have rights over how your personal information is used, including:**

  * The right to object to our processing of your data.

  * The right to request that your information be erased or restricted from further use.

  * The right to request a copy of the information we hold about you.

  * The right to correct, amend or update information you have given us (where you have an account with us you can also do this by logging in and updating your information).

  * The right to contest any automated decision we make about you. An automated decision is a decision taken without any human intervention which has legal consequences (e.g. credit checking). We don’t typically carry out automated decision making but, if we do, we will make it clear where such decisions are being made.

To exercise any of the above rights please contact our Data Protection Officer, on privacy@theartstack.com. Please note that whilst we will carefully assess every request we receive we may not always have to comply. When this happens, we will explain why.

**Looking After Your Information**

We take steps to make sure your information is protected and to delete it securely when we no longer need it. We only keep your information for as long as required to provide you with the services you request, for the purposes outlined in this policy and for any legal purposes for which we are obliged to keep the information.

**Contact Us**

If you have any questions about this notice, or how we handle your information, please be in touch, our Data Protection Officer is here to help: [privacy@theartstack.com](mailto:privacy@theartstack.com) There’s also the Information Commissioner's Office (ICO) although we encourage you to try and let us help you first.
